## Michael CLAUDE

- 06 89 18 79 85
- michael.claude.web@gmail.com
- 15 rue Rollin 75005 Paris

#### **ABOUT**

33 years old with 10 years of experience in different web professions but mainly in front web integration and development. Versatile, autonomous, I have good adaptability and good human contact. I put my skills and my multiple experiences to good use to best meet the needs and challenges that are exposed to

#### LANGUAGES

French
English
Spanish

#### **SKILLS**

#### Web integration

Html/CSS/SCSS,Boostrap 4, Responsive design, UI/UX Conception, Media Queries

#### Web front development

Javascript/Jquery/Ajax, Angular 1, Angular 2+, git, json

#### CMS

Wordpress, woocommerce, Joomla

#### Web back development

PHP, SQL, creation of databases

#### Softwares

Visual studio code, Sublime Text 3, Photoshop, After Effects, Final cut, ableton live.

#### **TRAINING**

**2009** CFA com (alternation) Multimedia scriptwriting license and Open Distance Training

**2008** CFA com (alternation) BTS, TIM (Multimedia Integration Technician)

**2006** CFA com (alternation) Year Upgrade Art

**2005** lycée Uruguay France (Avon) Tray STT Action Commercial Communication

#### **HOBBIES**

**Music**: musician, drums, percussions, composition, MAO + bands websites

**Social:** volunteering in an association: distribution of food and clothing to homeless people + website

**Environment**: Help in an association of shared gardens + website

### WEB FRONT INTEGRATOR DEVELOPER

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (10 years)**

From 2010 to the present day | Front & back Web development, e-commerce, intégration, project management, UI/UX conception, customer support | Freelance (in parallel with my salary activities)

Digikoder (from 2010 to present day) for my customers as freelancer >> Design and management of various web / multimedia projects, graphic models, ergonomics, video editing, management of domain names, shared and dedicated OVH web hosts (webmin/ubuntu).

- >> Implementation of several websites with CMS wordpress/joomla and html5/css3/javascript/jquery/php/ajax, SEO, speed, security optimisations.
- >> Driving and conceptualizing personal projects, websites, web and mobile applications (phonegap).
- >> Creation of **E-commerce** sites with CMS, wordpress woocommerce
- > Greenpoint: (2019), NetResto, Nouslibertins.com: (2018)
  Integration of front and back office web interfaces html, css, sass, responsive design in a small team.
- > One color: (2015 2017)

Creation of websites in html, css, js ,ajax, php, wordpress, woocommerce for a renowned photographer Frédérique Mercier as well as for its customers including the migration of a large online clothing store (payment system, inventory management, import of products, price update). Seo optimisations

> Teaminside : ( 2015 )

Integration / web development front responsive design for the new website of the MMA (assurance).

> Living Actor : ( 2014 )

Integration of the new website from graphic models in html, css, javascript, responsive design.

2019-2020 | Front web developer | CIPAV (Angular2+/js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/scss/Jira) - OEC

> Integration of the ISD team for the following mission:

Development and redesign of internal business applications with Angular

- > Integration of graphic models for business applications and intranet content
- > Self training on new REACTjs, Angular2, VueJS technologies

2017-2018 | Front web developer / Project Manager | AB PRODUCTION (Angular2+/js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/ajax/grunt/bower/scss/Jira) - OEC

- > Integration of the ISD team for the following mission:
- >> redesign and production of new business tools to replace the company's aging business software. (creation of channel programming playlists, cross-checking of data, management of data and users, etc.)
- >> set up and training on the angular-cli tool and the teamwork task manager + agile work methodology.

## 2017 | Front web developer / Project Manager | Publicis Conseil (js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/ajax/grunt/bower/scss/gitlab/Jira) - OEC

- > Replacement of a web project manager, discussions with the ACCOR hotels client, project management for 3 months:
- >> management / finalization of the redesign of the ACCOR hotel group site, addition of functionalities, debugging, optimizations.
- >> creation, management of tickets, customer exchanges, meetings, distribution of tasks to teams.
- >> ergonomic, technical and functional analyzes to meet customer needs.
- > Front web developer and integrator:
- >> Integration of a team of developers to fix bugs, add various functionalities and improvements on the different sites of publicis group customers (ACCOR, Maison du monde, Legrand ...).
- >> Getting started with the different development tools (git, phpstorm, gitlab, Nextdeplox (vm tool), bower, sass, grunt).

## 2016 | Front web developer | Louis Vuitton - Seloger.com (SSII - CDI) (js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/git/ajax/grunt/bower/scss)

- > Integration of a developers team to manage bug tickets, adding various features and improvements on the various sites of Valtech group customers (Eres, Louis Vuitton, L'Oréal).
- >> Getting started with the different development tools (git, webstorm, bower, sass, grunt).
- >> Integration of the Valtech development team at Louis Vuitton as a web front developer to optimize the accessibility of the new Louis Vuitton 2017 site, various optimizations, ticket management, addition of new functionalities.
- > SELOGER.COM:
- >> Resumption and finalization of a project for Seloger-finance: development of a conditional navigation system between several stages of an application intended to fill in a financing file for the acquisition of goods referenced at Seloger.com through different forms.

## 2014 | Front web developer, project manager, UI / UX design, integrator, project management | Digikoder (js vanilla/AngularJS 1/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/ajax/wordpress/woocommerce)

- > Creation of a restaurant website in Ibiza, wordpress responsive design, support and exchanges with the client to carry out the project + collaboration with SEO specialists.
- > Design and production of a local social network build with an HTML5 hybrid mobile application, the Intel XDK (cordova) tool and angularJS1 for the website. Phonegap migration at the end of the project.
- > Creation of a responsive design website in media-queries without frameworks.
- > Responsive design for the new MMA website (mission with a face-to-face service provider)

### 2014 | Front & Back web developer, technical project manager | Res-novae (CDI)

(js vanilla/HTML5/CSS3/PHP/ajax/joomla/SQL/Adobe AIR)

- > Development, monitoring and optimization of a desktop application for BEL company salespeople allowing to consult a media bank and consult news (html5 / css3 / javascript / AIR).
- > Getting started with the AIR javascript API to set up the deployment system for updates in the application from zip files generated on the back office.
- > Graphic, ergonomic and functional optimizations according to customer requests and the IT department.
- > Establishment of a back office to manage users, generate document updates, statistics and news.

# 2009-2013 | Front / back web developer / designer, project manager, webmaster, multimedia integrator, video editor, graphic designer | Mediaways (CDI) (js vanilla/jquery/HTML5/CSS3/PHP/ajax/joomla/SQL/joomla)

- > Project management, design and implementation of the new website, the new graphic charter using joomla.
- > Total overhaul of the Rich media web solution for text / image / video synchronization offered by the company (IER, Sanofi, Numéricable, Lafarge, SNCF) SNCF example:
- > Initiation, conceptualization and management of a complex web application project of automated and simplified generation of the web solution directly online (image, text and video synchronization online, graphic personalization assisted in real time, automatic generation of invoices according to actions carried out, management of user access to different projects, etc.).
- > Realization of various web projects (photo library), debugging, optimization / technological developments, customer assistance / training.

#### 2008 - 2009 - Webmaster Assistant / multimedia designer - France Télécom - 94 : (Alternation).

- > animation of the France Telecom customer relations service intranet network at company headquarters, creation of html / css / javascript charted and scalable pages.
- > realization of a project of interactive virtual visit of a France Telecom call center in 3D with pre-calculated videos and interconnected between them in a Flash interface.

#### 2006 - 2008 - multimedia designer- BeeLIGHT agence numérique - 75 (Alternation) :

- > creation of a slideshow configurator in flash / XML.
- > integration and development of a desktop application with Director and the Lingo language (ancestor of Flash).
- > video editing, 3D modeling, animation and integration of flash banners.